<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" >
  <channel>
    <title>Leasing Dispute on Bobo Law Firm</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/leasing-dispute/</link>
    <description>Recent Posts in Leasing Dispute on Bobo Law Firm</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.155.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>email@example.com (Author Name)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>email@example.com (Author Name)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:36:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/leasing-dispute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>【Success Case】Delinquent Tenant Missing and Behind on Rent? Attorney Assists with Compulsory Execution to Successfully Reclaim Property</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/categories/cases/case-civil-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>email@example.com (Author Name)</author>
      <dc:creator>A-Bo-Bo Attorney at Law</dc:creator>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/categories/cases/case-civil-01/</guid>
      <description>The tenant fell behind on rent for over six months and avoided all contact. The attorney obtained a favorable judgment through litigation and applied for compulsory execution, successfully completing the property handover.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-overview&#34;&gt;Case Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The client, Mr. Chen (pseudonym), leased an apartment in Taipei City to a tenant. Initially, rent was paid on time; however, after six months, the tenant began using excuses to delay payments and eventually stopped answering calls and messages. The total rent arrears exceeded six months.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Chen attempted to resolve the issue in person but found the door locked. Worried that changing the locks himself might violate laws regarding &amp;ldquo;Coercion&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Trespassing,&amp;rdquo; leaving him helpless against the squatter, he entrusted our firm to handle the matter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-strategy--proceedings&#34;&gt;Legal Strategy &amp;amp; Proceedings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-issuing-a-formal-demand-letter-termination-of-contract&#34;&gt;Step 1: Issuing a Formal Demand Letter (Termination of Contract)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Legal procedures rely on evidence. Attorney A-Bo-Bo first assisted in sending a &amp;ldquo;Formal Demand Letter&amp;rdquo; (Legal Notice), setting a reasonable deadline for the tenant to pay the arrears. Once the deadline passed, we issued a notice to &amp;ldquo;Terminate the Lease Agreement&amp;rdquo; in accordance with Article 440 of the Civil Code, effectively stripping the tenant of their legal right to possession.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-filing-a-lawsuit-for-eviction-and-recovery-of-premises&#34;&gt;Step 2: Filing a Lawsuit for Eviction and Recovery of Premises&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the tenant continued to ignore the situation, we immediately filed a lawsuit for &amp;ldquo;Eviction and Recovery of Premises&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Payment of Rent Arrears.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;In court, the attorney presented the complete lease agreement, remittance records, and the return receipt of the formal demand letter. After review, the judge swiftly rendered a &lt;strong&gt;favorable judgment&lt;/strong&gt; for Mr. Chen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-application-for-compulsory-execution&#34;&gt;Step 3: Application for Compulsory Execution&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the judgment, the tenant refused to vacate. The attorney immediately applied to the Civil Execution Department of the Court for &amp;ldquo;Compulsory Execution.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Accompanied by a Court Clerk and local police officers, a locksmith was called to open the door. After an inventory of the items inside, the tenant&amp;rsquo;s possession was officially terminated, and the property was formally handed back to Mr. Chen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;// Case Timeline&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;January: Issued Formal Demand Letter for arrears.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;February: Formally filed the lawsuit.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;May: Obtained favorable judgment (Judgment by Default/One-Sided Argument).&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;July: On-site Compulsory Execution and Property Handover.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>Case Studies</category>
      <enclosure url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1560518883-ce09059eeffa?ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=800&amp;q=80" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>